[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard
knowledge is power
what's up guys welcome to the junk hair
love podcast today's recommendation is
in the form of a book I finished this
one up audio book style this a.m. it is
called awareness by Anthony DeMaio
I got this recommendation myself from
hearing that Tim Ferriss I don't know if
somebody gifted it he gifted it to
somebody I think it was a constant gift
that he would give to friends was this
book and I saw that a couple weeks ago
or read about it I heard about it I was
like well I trust that because I trust
that guy definitely check out his
podcast too or any of his books that's
another great recommendation there Tim
Ferriss but uh the book recommendation
awareness by Anthony DeMaio check it out
it's great today's episode with Rebecca
Wilde it's quite fantastic fantastical I
hope you guys are doing well hope you
guys are holding your loved ones close I
hope you're looking yourself in the
mirror and say and I love you too I hope
you're feeling healthy
I hope you're feeling loved I'll be
feeling whole don't forget to don't
forget to FaceTime your your extrovert
friends you know don't forget to to
reach out to the ones who are you know
not dealing so well with with with being
at home you know look out for each other
take care yourself let's get wrong
mostly I I've been able to not have to
edit much like it at the bit at the very
beginning it was actually kind of funny
because I was so self-conscious and like
I realized that I said words way too
often or I didn't enunciate very well
and so at the beginning my first like 10
episodes I kept like editing my voice
like I was like oh I wish I didn't say
that or like how would someone be
talking something serious and I would
try to throw like a just like a weird
joke in or something that didn't hit and
so I'd be listening back to it and I'm I
go I should take the head of help like
but it's funny all right it's like dude
that's it's a conversation that happened
you can't rewind like exactly just who
you are the person is totally fine like
they're comfortable it's a it's
interesting we're like so self-critical
of ourselves but we're just who we are
you know we try to catch it before
someone else does
yeah this weird protection method like
now I'm gonna find my flaws that would
people and point it out I'm gonna find
it first yeah you can't you can't throw
it out you can't stab me with with the
weapon that I took back but my favorite
thing about that is noticing that you
are a beginner in something and that if
it is your truth then it doesn't really
matter what people say it doesn't matter
if you've done this one time or 1000
times or if you are doing it with like
low-budget stuff or a million dollar
production they're still gonna be haters
there's gonna be critics so it doesn't
matter yeah I think that we all think
that we're like like just because I'm
making a podcast doesn't mean that I am
trying to compete with all the top
podcasts no like I'm just doing what the
level I'm at like when I make a song I'm
not trying to say that I'm better than
Drake I'm just making a song cuz I'm a
human being who hears music you know
like whatever it's crazy we we put a lot
on ourselves but I think that we put a
lot on ourselves because we we
accidentally kind of put a lot of other
people too like it's just our way of of
living like the same things that we do
to other people they're doing to us yes
and when you kind of slow it down you're
like I don't even do that
don't you do that to them because I
don't want them do it to me exactly or
Jake can I tell you a secret
tell me secret recording Oh then I will
tell you a secret okay the whole world
is secret when I liked when you were
changing your platform a little bit the
direction that you were going with it is
the same time that I was doing my
schooling and so I was seeing it seeing
it seeing it and I was watching it grow
and there was a part of me like a there
was a yucky part that got really jealous
and I did not like how that felt like
what the heck I'd like this person why
do I feel like me about it so I had
actually pause like why are those
feelings creeping up when the person
like you Jake were doing something
beautiful you were making a difference
and why was it feeling like a threat to
me I was my own self like criticism
right I'm not where you're at yet like I
I'm going through a program that I'm
paying for and I'm going to make money
by doing it making different sounds like
crap and then there's part of me that
feel bad for charging for it when you're
out here making a difference just by
people listening to your podcast
alright and there was so many elements
that I actually sat down with a notebook
like why did this bother me and
to really observe my own that's actually
savage yes but it's the same day you
asked me if I would do the podcast are
you serious yes sir I was like no the
more the more that this is available to
everyone the more change we can make yes
the more avenues people have the more
they see it like you know house we're
scrolling through stuff yeah it's gonna
make a difference and that's what
matters like that's the core of all of
this yeah and then not even an hour
later you're like hey want to come on
the podcast like yes yes whose life is
so curious like that isn't it like it
was a lie I think I was looking back
through text this morning and I texted
you and you're like why did you have me
on the podcast or why'd you ask me and I
was like kind of told dis and stuff and
then the last thing I was like and
honestly intuition mmm like I like I
mean who knows what that word really
means right like who knows but like I
don't know when you follow it and you
just kind of trust it and you're just
like you see like how this person is
doing this thing like you let's let's
expand on that you know and you just
follow it it seems like so far it's been
going pretty well for me and it seems
like I feel so [__] fulfilled at the
end of these podcasts okay like it's in
it's it's something new like I you know
I've been feeding my ego my whole life
like like let's be popular on stage like
oh you guys gonna chant my name I love
that you know like of course but but
this is something new this is like a
it's like a popularity not for me like I
like I don't I don't take it for myself
I'm like it's just like a I know it's
like it it's reaffirmation I guess but
it's it's it's great I love it it's cool
I'm super happy to have you thank you
for having it yeah it's a new experience
for me and it's fun actually I'm not as
nervous as I thought that I was going to
be yeah my mouth is working it's working
I'm saying words words I pulled this up
because I would like to start with this
you sent me this this is I'm just gonna
read this and then I would love for you
to explain what it is okay the wild
woman
is a warrior a goddess of the wilderness
who loves herself at any form who honors
her body with food from the earth who
connects with nature as a way to feel
grounded who strives to get back to a
simple way of living
clutter less chemicals less stress more
fresh air more self-love more living be
wild be well you said that to make any
tell me about that is my big ol motto
that I've learned to live by anytime
then I feel myself getting like out of
control it's those words that I've
written over and over and over and over
again that I've made me more grounded
and made me feel stable cuz like I've
mentioned before I kind of like to have
control but you can only control so much
in your life and most of that is your
reaction to what happens and so when it
comes to being like wild and being well
that's it it's it's taking from the
earth to get back to yourself like the
food that we put in our bodies drinking
enough water going out into nature
literally saved my life these things
have made my life worth living and I
just wanted to be able to encompass that
into one single post or one visual aid
that people could reference yeah so that
way maybe they could remind it be
reminded to slow down and do those
things as well yeah it's kind of like a
it's crazy I have a thing written on the
wall you give things power and it like
flirts with my mind all the time like it
was a I didn't grow up with like a dead
set value structure or any of those
things and so like I kind of just like
rejected like being 100% for sure about
things or or any of that um but I think
when you give things power you can take
like what's this big idea what's this
thing like Oh like all these things have
helped me in how can I make my brain
remember all those things but not make
it too complicated yeah and you did
condense it down make you give you gave
this paragraph power and it seems like
it's given a lot of life to or a lot of
power to your life absolutely but now
you're like extending it like how can I
make this Creed this thing here shine to
other people to other women yes have you
had like have you had good experiences
with other people like have other people
read it and any of you or do you have
clients yet or do you have okay how do
they feel about it we're that with that
oh they they resonate with it really
well
it becomes like it's attainable and it's
simplified down to like oh I can do that
it's a good reminder and I'm just really
proud of the people that I have been
working with because they they seem to
sit down because they're at their wit's
end
they're in the middle of the chaos and
we pick it apart and we simplify it down
to things that they can get that power
from right and by that I mean
empowerment as most of the time we're
really confused about what we can and
cannot control and like you said what
what we have are all that we have is
like what we give our attention to we
give the power to right so if you can
simplify it down into like I want this
and then give all of your attention to
those things there's a lot more success
right I think that that's similar I
don't like it I mean I think that's
somewhere I was thinking about I've
mentioned this before on the inside my
glasses here I put the word lion and for
me and then in our upstairs bathroom I
have there's like this black and white
like it's the whole wall just like this
lion in the morning and like but that's
kind of what I did like it's kind of
only for me I haven't really formed I
think I want to form like a junkyard
love like a powerful badass paragraph
like you have I come out there yeah I
really like that but I think it's slowly
forming right but for now for me you
know even though we're drunker I'd love
but lion is just like all these things
that I install in myself so it's like
when I say lion in my head or I like
remember to look out at the corner of my
eye with my glasses here I see in the
morning I'm like remember what that
means man it's like oh I'm a good person
I'm okay I'm safe and then and then for
me I'm like I'm also a badass and so I
literally straightened my posture
anytime I remember to read the word lion
I I like I ground myself my cam here in
this moment like whatever I was just
crazy thinking about let's let's realize
that's a thought let's be right here in
this room you know it helps me that it's
grounding right like you talked about
grounding to we look back at our text
messages and I was like I definitely
want to talk about that you talk about
getting out in nature
grounding these are for me I feel like
when I I've always liked ground a nature
like like getting outside I've always
enjoyed up in like a skateboarder I'm
like an outdoor person but there was you
I feel like I was super disconnected it
from it for many years like it was like
oh it's raining I'm like going outside
like I'm not oh it's not the perfect
weather I'm like going out so I'm
staying that like it but now I'm like oh
if I want to walk down to the post
office that doesn't matter if it's
raining or not that's just a thing
that's happening and I now have I now
like I'm comfortable with going out to
the woods by myself and going and runs
and going cold water lake up there it's
my [__] favorite place like I just
love going on runs out there
i I I was very detached from I almost
saw like the people who hiked in like
going out in nature and people who
enjoyed outside as like a personality
trait as like a well that's just a thing
that like those kind of people do like
like a hiking people or give you people
or you know like because we we try to
conceptualize things of why we don't do
them and we and we really like backing
it up of like well that's just not my
thing that's their thing but I think
that as a human we live in the craziest
[__] world ever like it's so crazy
that we just have these little boxes
that make magic for us at all times and
we have everything at our fingertips but
like getting outside is this feeling the
being out in nature is this is this
thing that like every human has the
ability to kind of connect to and it it
reminds you it makes you feel
significant and significant at the same
time I always say you take me to a place
where I feel small and it's the best
thing for me because a lot of things
happen and they're overwhelming and they
feel really really big and you feel like
you're the only person in the world that
will understand what's going on but when
you go out and you do that hard hike and
you get to the very top and you see that
huge mountain or huge waterfall or huge
cavern whatever it is it's bigger than
you yeah and it took a long time to get
there yeah that's just really good ah
sometimes I go out there and after a
strenuous hike you're you know you're
exhausted and but also proud because you
just defeated something you weren't sure
if you could accomplish and then there's
that beautiful view and that's where I
get my actual like emotional release
yeah I'll sit there and cry cuz it's so
pretty and look at what I get to see and
here I was stressing out about something
stupid or insignificant rather and then
there's this beautiful thing sitting in
front of me I'm gonna stay here all day
and I don't have cell phone service and
it's awesome it's so weird to think
about like because I think that okay so
me three years ago I'm in the depths of
my anxiety and someone's like you need
to go for a run and you'll feel better I
think what are you like what do you mean
like what do you you don't just get like
a magic fairy that gets to the end and
at the end of your hike that's like
alright here you go you know but but i
but it really is a it's it's a feeling
it's it's a it's something that we don't
super have words for and I think it is
just that like a reminder of like what
this all is about you know you takes you
out of your maze of your head that we
all have we all have a maze and we are
in sometimes being in that maze and like
the stuff they give this gives us
anxiety isn't always unrealistic like
sometimes it is but sometimes it's like
we're just thinking about crazy and big
stuff in our life for big decisions and
for me like getting out into the woods
and just like feeling that it it helps
clear it out
where are your go-to hiked places like
where are some places that stand out oh
yeah
anywhere and everywhere I go I have the
all trails app and talking about the all
trails app and I have it it's just all
trails and it's like a little green tree
thing and you can its GPS so you can
type in anywhere that you want to go or
you can literally look up the location
that you're at and it will tell you any
hikes that are near you it'll tell you
the distance that it is if they allow
pets if they're not so good like family
friendly how hard it is the incline and
then you can also download the map so if
you're someone that's afraid to do it
because you don't to get lost you can
download the map and it will track you
all the way to the end and all the way
back yeah it's my most favorite thing on
the planet anytime someone says where
should I go hiking I just send them the
link to the app that's so great and then
my favorite thing about it is you can
look at comments too so you can see if
there's any road closures or if there's
any safety things to worry about
or lately with the snow there's been
some comments like don't go up there
there's snow and I'm like yes there's no
I'm gonna take my snowshoes
get my butt out there but if it was my
car I'd be like well I can't even get up
there exactly then you know what clothes
to take with food to take that's so cool
it's kind of you're the Waze app I think
it's a driving applica Maps app Waze I
have heard yeah that's kind of like like
kind of like that where like if you're
driving on the freeway and someone sees
like a brokedown car they can like put
on their like hey there's a brokedown
car on the side of exit whatever 48 yeah
helps get you over the hazard areas
that's cool like humans really helping
each other out if you think about like
like all the the different contributions
that it takes to make those cool things
like that app exactly and I think it was
only like 20 bucks a year for the
advanced version where you could
download all the different kinds of maps
topography maps and the forestry maps
road maps have you ever had to fight any
Cougars on your hikes
no but I have seen bear you've seen a
bear yeah I have not seen any Cougars on
the trail but that's probably because
they're really stealthy and quiet but
bears those things you walk around a
corner and there's a bear there then
they kind of freak out you freak out and
they like they make so much noise when
they're running through the woods and
normally I don't hike without some sort
of protection ray of course I agree
that's a good thing
what can you tell me about your bear
story is it like as intense as it seemed
so it was literally just that like
you're hiking around like oh this is
beautiful
oh they smell bears have a scent boy it
kind of sounds like a really really
really wet dog it's like that's not a
weird smell in the middle of they
probably don't take many baths with him
no they should they have a human who
just washes their belly for him come on
down bring your bears more bears kids no
it was literally that just walking
around the corner and there's a bear
there and I got startled and it got
startled and then it went a different
direction it was were you able to like
chill after that though because I feel
like I would be like I'm gonna go home
lay down okay um I just listened a lot
more intently like my senses were able
to like are heightened
yet I figure it was afraid of me as well
and so I just kept going made a little
closer attention yeah it's a it's
another thing that's like it's scary but
it's also like after
fact it is kind of an incredible thing
like we our lives are so disconnected
like there's if it's not a zoo or on the
TV you don't see bears and then you like
kind of get reminded of like oh yeah
[__] that's real
you know that's it's in it again makes
you feel significant and insignificant
yeah in a way definitely pay attention
yeah and that's why I always or I guess
I never wear like headphones or anything
because I want to hear all little cracks
and snaps of the twigs and my own
footsteps my own breath just very
interesting I would never want to cover
that up just for safety reason the end
connection with earth I I think that it
it puts us into like this weird flow
State for sure
like I mean hiking like just hearing
your breath in like you can almost
there's almost so much that there's
nothing but also so much going on when
you're hiking right like like every tree
is so intricate in all the different
edges of the trail and sometimes when
it's not like a super easy trail to like
and you're just going you're just going
it kind of makes you forget about your
other [__] and you're just in that
moment it's really a present moment
forcing situation I so I had a I was
hiking a few months back and I I was up
by myself and I do at the first part I
had headphones in and I listen to music
and I was like I get like a mile and a
half and I have like my little arms no
no that's why I asked about cures
because I at Coldwater there's like
signs up that that say like watch out
for Cougars and so like obviously just
as a human you're like oh I'm [__]
terrified but I'm cool about that let's
just a sign whatever but I went and I
was like a mile and a half in and I I
wanted to get like good motivation at
starting so I had hit my headphones on I
got to my first spot and and and for me
I smoked weed when I go on hikes
sometimes and so I got my first spot and
I was like started smoking and I put my
headphones off I'm gonna start hearing
just just the screaming house of coyotes
and I was like oh man I was like okay
and i i i hadn't seen anybody yet there
it was pretty early and then but it made
me start thinking and kind of pulled me
out I was like do I like if a coyote
attacks me what do I do like
or do coyotes attack in packs or in so I
started getting me like really realizing
I'm kind of dumb like I didn't really
think and then obviously of course I'm
like oh well coyotes like I think they
probably wouldn't really attack me
unless there's like 20 of them right but
then I'm like but also don't you know
what that cougar and it's just funny
like I I once you get that thought in
your mind like the whole rest of my hike
I would get going I'm good and I'm at 45
minutes and then also I remember about
the Cougar and the Coyotes I'm like oh
shoot you started listening more you
didn't turn around no I got going guys
yeah I love it was i well so I also have
this thing and I don't I don't know if
this is like a super healthy thing but
it helps me like pushing into my edge
and not like bow down to my like [__]
side I know that's a kind of crappy word
but like I kind of I kind of like
putting myself in feel fearful positions
yes and pushing past it because in the
end you always win you know like yeah
you learn what survivable yeah like if
you like exploring different states of
consciousness and in exploring different
boundaries that you didn't know you had
like getting too uncomfortable spots and
realizing that you can push past is like
this crazy unlocking thing as a human
for me so I like obviously not all the
time like sometimes misses you there's a
difference between trusting your
intuition and pushing yourself past like
an anxiety that you that you're just
aware of there's a difference there
because that anxiety is actually meant
to keep you alive that's his purpose so
we can honor that like I'm scared so
what do I do
take my headphones out pay attention and
I keep pushing unless your intuition
kicks in and then you're like no wait
this is completely unsafe conditions
right it's getting dark the animals are
coming out I'm gonna turn back yeah
you've got to be able to like have that
a little conversation with yourself like
don't bow down with it but also just be
like you can do it or maybe it's time to
turn back I have to do that because when
I'm out in nature on the way to the cool
spot if I'm not paying attention to the
beauty of nature
I'll pay attention to the physical
ailments like I have a broken foot that
I never really took care of so it'll egg
and I'll focus on that No let's focus on
the beauty of this or like take a deep
breath
get something out of it besides like
focusing on my body hurting cuz hiking
is a physical activity it is hard you
have a pack on depends on how long your
you're going like I did a 25 mile hike
in one day and it was extremely
difficult it was up the Asguard past the
enchantments of Leavenworth area it was
the hardest thing I've ever done but how
do you get through it one step at a time
and it was worth it was the most
incredible place I've ever been in my
whole life I'm not bad there and I did
it Jake that's the thing oh yeah
Congrats I didn't think I could I was
like you know not my best shape but I
just kept going one foot in front of the
other and got done what was how did you
start like before you had done this I
could have you done anything like any
anywhere near that long before not at
all tell me about link your mindset
before versus your mindset after oh man
it was incredible what I was able to
achieve because in the back of my mind I
always knew like I could turn back and
it was a thru-hike so it wasn't a loop
so if I made it past a certain point I
might as well just finish it all the way
yeah yeah and the Asguard that passed
specifically the hardest part is the
beginning chunk if I can get through
that I can get through the end like it's
the physical exhaustion of doing the
first few like the first seven miles the
hardest thing but going back down that
pass is dangerous
yeah and I wouldn't want to do that so
just kept going it was daunting like
grueling to keep going the rest the way
because the beauty of the mountain kind
of it turned into dirt like they call it
[Music]
the dead miles I think something along
those lines was just so good nothing
kills me there's nothing to look at is
what it is the beauty is what keeps you
moving forward through the past because
there's so many different places you can
look different glacial lakes and
everything but when it comes to the
mindset of that at first I was like I'm
not gonna pay attention to the miles
logged or the miles I have left I'm just
gonna keep going I signed up for this
it's an experience and I'm gonna make it
through it right yeah once you once you
set out it it's cool like making that
goal for yourself like I'm gonna do this
again I'm gonna there's a lot of our a
lot of our lives a lot of us in our life
we don't do things like that I feel like
we don't
put a peg in it and say like I gotta do
this for me not for anybody else before
me
I'm the most stubborn human I know if I
say I'm gonna do it I have to prove it
to myself I'm not going to give up I
just have to do it yeah I'm sure that's
helped shape you into into the more
badass version of yourself in many ways
yes I view it as a positive but
sometimes it does it's actually like a
barrier for me like why can't you be a
little bit more flexible a little less
they come my husband my rigidity is
something that we battle often because
I'm like now I made up my mind and doing
it it's like well what if that might not
be the safest way or could you go a
different weekend with other people or
there's you know multiple scenarios I
grew up with where my rigidity isn't
always the best thing but when it comes
to like a success or a goal I feel like
it's like the ultimate for for people
like who are always kind of just like
having a little battle in their mind
like to insert a situation where you're
like I'm gonna hear both voices of my
doubt and my and my good beast but like
I've got to do this thing to make sure
I'm listening to the good beast like a
lot of times taking out choice it's like
you said oh can you go a different day
can you go with these different people a
lot of times bringing in choices into
the situation will be enough to [__]
me and I won't go like like oh I want to
go on a hike today like just leave at 8
a.m. but then if I you know I love going
with friends sometimes but like if i
text friends and then they're like oh
can we go go at nine and they're like oh
who should I invite it turns into this
big thing it's rather than just like
choosing to go mm-hmm with that one if
you want to go on that hike you go and
it works for you like it only works for
you at that time of day and you set the
time and then you make sure you tell all
the people like all the details I'm
leaving at this time we're meeting at
8:00 I need to be back by 2:00 right can
you go cuz then there's no that's a good
that's a good you know boundaries yeah I
think where we kind of live in a world
especially when comes to texting and
stuff right where we live in a world
where we're afraid to like come at them
with like hey here's what I'm doing love
you to join me Mike
rather than like a hey I was thinking
about this mountain have you ever heard
of it and there's this hike and we could
like there
all these options because you want to
make the other your friend comfortable
and you want to give them options but I
think you're right I think a lot of us
are a little healthier when we just pick
what we're doing and say do this I would
love for you to join me yeah if you've
been a people-pleaser of any part of
your life then that's like a habit
that's gonna carry into whatever you're
doing and as we're becoming more of our
own person knowing what we want to do
it's not being like assertive or
aggressive with it you're just like hey
this is the plan that works me can you
come if not I'm gonna go by myself right
thank you I feel like I find that people
actually respect that like you there's
always a little bit of a fear like I
don't want my friend to think that I'm
like being too Stern or being like a
hard-ass but most the time your friends
are like cool awesome
I got support you like I'm an early
riser I want to beat the traffic I want
to be there before sunrise and then I
want to be home to make dinner and like
wind down actually a lot of people
aren't like that a lot of my friends
aren't like that look say so there I
know that so there's some wiggle room
like well okay I want to leave it for
should we leave at 6:00 then thank you I
don't know it just depends on the
situation for sure but if it's something
that's important to you make sure make
sure it happens yeah I agree
tell me I want to talk about I want to
talk about more of your business and
more of your coaching okay um tell me
about before so so what led you to even
want to start doing this I'm wanting to
start helping people like what were you
a different person before did you think
differently what was the jump from like
giving yourself this like I should try
this thing you know I want to hear about
it as much as it was a jump it was also
a push because I've been doing hair for
ten years now and I noticed that the
more that I do hair and lashes the more
my neck was acting up
and I've always I've always had a bad
like neck I had a neck injury and when I
looked down to look at the lashes that
I'm doing or raise my arms to do hair
like that it started to really really
bother me and then I would start to go
you know like an old TV that goes and
goes from like axe
screen down to nothing yes my left I
would do that oh that's terrifying yeah
so then I would look up and it was like
go back to normal
look down gone how my visions going away
so I'll just close my eye just the one
eye and do lashes what's happening to me
and then just stabbing someone in the
eyes er no no no no no I'm very careful
but then I started to get what I thought
was like a facial paralysis because then
I started to be my bottom eyelid and my
cheek and then down my lip then my
tongue then my throat like it just kept
progressing but it wasn't actually
paralyzed it just was this heavy hot
fire
it was awful and I looked it was only a
last thing like 30 seconds but I looked
in the mirror and like tried to express
my face and it still had movement but
the pain was so severe that just makes
you like and I would shake and then I
would just pass and it was only when I
was working oh no so then I went to a
chiropractor and I don't have health
insurance so I went to the chiropractor
and I explained to her what was going on
just like you need to go get an x-ray
and I was like an x-ray so then I tried
acupuncture and she in the same spot in
my neck I didn't I didn't say anything
like a little test like what do people
know tell me what I don't know about my
body so she did her little thing she's
like hey I'm not gonna put needles on
this side cuz I feel like those muscles
are holding your spine in place like I'm
not gonna release them I think they're
important you need to go get an x-ray so
that was the same area you were kind of
feeling yes so then I went to the
radiology clinic I was like look both
doctor you know both professionals said
I should get an x-ray what can you do
for me I don't have insurance and you
know what they take out of pocket it was
a hundred and eleven dollars cash it's
cool yeah that's a lucky number yes it
is it was amazing so I took that x-ray
back to the chiropractor and she so when
your spine is in alignment all of your
blood vessels and nerve endings sit in
these little columns perfectly but my
neck injury was a forceful frontward
injury and it it made me have a
permanent or the reverse cervical spine
and so as I'm looking down all my blood
vessels and nerve endings are actually
getting like pinched or severed
and so doing that motion over and over
and over maybe how this happened to my
face so she said hey Rebecca I think
it's time that you find a different
career and this is my identity it's what
it's the business that I built it's Who
I am it's what I love my favorite part
about the salon is actually the
connection with people and being able to
be someone that they could turn to with
all of their problems without judgement
or ridicule and so I got on they'll
Google I was like um how can I help
people without going to college for five
years whatever it would take and
coaching popped up I was like oh my god
it's the thing so I clicked on it and I
called the school and it is it is a
thing and so there's there's multiple
avenues that people could go down when
it comes to getting help with something
there's the counselors doctors you know
if it's for a physical thing they could
they could have a trainer or there's
nutritionist when it comes to diet but
like a coach kind of encompasses all of
that except for we do not diagnose or
treat you what we do is hold space for
you to tell your story to say what you
want we empower you to make the choices
that align with those things and we work
side-by-side with doctors or
psychologists so say that you have a
team all everyone needs a team but we
you could sign a release form and then
we can work side-by-side with those
people so if you are diagnosed with a
certain health disease like a lifestyle
disease I can talk with your doctor and
we can make a plan and then I'm here I'm
more accessible a doctor takes a little
bit longer to get into but I'm someone
they could like text real quick but by
having this problem what do I do
right it's super important yeah it's
awesome it's been so fulfilling to me to
be able to help so many people beyond
the care dressing is basically what they
see in the mirror this is a much deeper
Avenue and it's it feels so good so
everything does happen for a reason and
I'm so excited to see where this
actually takes me and other people yeah
I mean it's great that you were able to
turn like a I mean you know you could
use diagnosed it sure like it like
something terrible really like you could
have you could have sat and pouted for
that
but I said you're like what all right
what do I got to do next and what's
great is you were fueled by you know not
like all right how do I keep making
money and just stay afloat you're like
what how I still help people how do I
still talk to people because I I think
that's a huge I always loved when I was
a kid any movie where there's like like
the town's like if it's like Chicago or
New York and there's like like the
barber shops I can always love that [__]
like where they would just talk and
there's like the old guys who would just
say it like it is there's somebody
playing chess over I always thought it
was the coolest thing but I think it's
because you know this world is has
always been in multiple ways like now
social media and phones and stuff and
all these other things so fast-paced but
we do have times where you're kind of
forced to sit right like you're getting
your lashes done you're getting your
hair done or your and in that that
person talking to you is a therapist in
many ways like a lot of times you
probably people would probably open up
to you before they realize they're
opening up to you they'd probably like
tell you more than they wanted to say
just because you make them comfortable
and yes but in and I think that these
areas are important I actually had
something on Facebook I posted a couple
months ago about I was comparing people
who do hair and stuff to dialysis
dialysis machines like like you take a
lot on and you do help a lot of people
you do hear a lot of people's I can't
drink it things and I'm sure like it's
encouraging but it's a essentially that
the post was make sure you're finding
ways to drain that from yourself to hold
everyone's problems absolutely that's
yeah exactly that's it's a huge thing
for me and but yeah I think I think it's
so cool like just really how you're
honest about your mindset like I think a
lot of hairdressers are actually or
hairdressers are in people who
consummate what is what's the word I'm
looking for like just general taking
care of people's like the cosmetologist
cosmetologist that's what okay that's
what how does the beauty people the
beauty people yeah I think they're
they're an important piece in our life
and it is cool that you're like that
because it's like you're your real
calling like what you really do is like
connect with people yes and like yeah
there's hair and there's eyelashes and
there's all these things that you can do
in that way but
like you still kept going with
connecting people when you got when you
were like feeling crappy it was so what
did you do to feel better from this like
nerve pinching like is it just you
didn't like overall I just powered
through it because I I have to make
money to pay my bills right and then I
had to make money to also pay for the
chiropractor and all of these other like
lifestyle changes that I needed to
incorporate into my life so I had to
find a balance and that I love the
chiropractor that I go to its dr. stacie
its energy and she just straight-up
asked me like what's the cost of your
health I think what is stopping you from
committing to your own progress and I'm
like me and I feel like monetarily I
can't and so we sat down and actually
made a plan she's really really good
with working we're [__] it's on 11th
Avenue synergy health solutions great it
was awesome I was like one of the most
life-changing things cuz she and she
didn't let me get away with anything
really cuz I'm very like guarded and
well it was I was really guarded in
private now not so much because I feel
like being open and honest like if I'm
doing it I'm also giving other people
permission it's like a catalyst for
being honest and I really feel like
that's where changes truly start and
when it came to my neck it wasn't just
about let's align your spine I was like
let's align your soul and that was it's
been life-changing it's been over a year
now or no almost a year I think I think
I got two so diagnosed yeah it yeah it's
the severity of the injury isn't
necessarily fixable but I'm doing what I
can to make it more manageable yeah you
work with it and so suffering it yeah
and I have to just be mindful about my
head placement and I have to I had to
learn how to say no in the salon because
I have I have my clients on I love them
and my lash ladies come every two weeks
so they're the majority of my schedule
so I'm looking down a lot I had to
create barriers and boundaries like with
myself so that way my schedule had gaps
in it which I'd never done before
it feels unproductive but I also had to
say no to clients when they needed to
switch because I could look at my sky
like I'm already doing four in a row I
know that if I do that then tomorrow I
won't be able to move my face yeah I
think little things like that are
important a lot of people who are
starting up businesses and listen to the
podcast and I think that's a good thing
to put up in in there it's like you like
it there's no point in doing six in a
row if you're fifth and six you're
feeling like crap and you aren't able to
show up as the person you want you in
most of the time if you're honest about
with your clients so especially if
they're kind of a friend level I'm like
oh I get it too right place it upon
ourselves that we have to make sure that
they're okay but we're not ever making
sure that we are I never take a lunch
unless it fits in my day I don't take
one for the last ten year it's a built
my business by being available by being
flexible with my time and by just
busting my butt right and there's any
entrepreneurs out there just make sure
you're taking time for yourself protect
your neck son protect your neck you know
insert Busta Rhymes right here do so the
the small neck injury is super
interesting because I were telling me
about that I was I don't know a ton
about it and you might enlighten me more
if I'm totally talking out of my butt
but um I was listening to somebody talk
about the way that we so say you're
right-handed you have your phone in your
right hand and you're kind of like as
you're walking texting you're kind of
like just the slightest angle your eyes
are looking down bottom right right
you know certain shoulder muscles are
flexed like it actually does we forget
we're growing at all times like it's
like we almost start growing in that
direction
something that like when I started doing
yoga and started just like being a
complete weirdo down here I'm just
exploring like whatever something that
was huge with a lot of my the back of my
neck pain was was my eyes and in like so
I would start because because you
noticed like if you're if you're looking
down bottom right and your eyes are kind
of looking also down bottom right in and
you like look up and down you can feel
in the backend neck sort of like a pole
listeners I mean if you could pretty
much just look down and then just move
your eyes only and you can kind of feel
a little bit of movement in the back in
neck so anyway what I started doing with
the yoga and stuff I start just being a
super weirdo and just as I'm stretching
just wow
and moving my mouth company letting my
eyes just rip open my eyes as wide as I
can and look to the top left and look to
the bottom left and and just like flex
my eyes my eye sockets like my whole
face all this stuff if you do that like
while you're stretching like no I feel
like you you start stretching muscles
that you're like oh that's been flexed
always give a break yeah did you have
anything like that and the chiropractor
not only do they like you know
manipulate your spine in some way but
they send you home with exercises to do
at home and I would stare at those
papers and like these are all so silly
but then I sat down and did them and all
it was was turning like okay so you're
sitting up straight you're sitting on
your butt be also sitting up straight
spinal alignment then take your chin and
just kind of give yourself the dub chin
look oh not too much and then just look
to one side of the other and now look
down
that's so much you can feel that now
look up at that angle when I look up my
whole head will start shaking because
I'd black out well no I just don't have
the muscle stability in that way and my
spine it isn't structurally sound at
that angle Wow okay
but you have like a built resilience in
structure and like all this hiking and
being active now seems to be like
holding this [__] pretty good there's
two parts to that this could be
crippling so I want to see the [__] now
before I can't you know before it
becomes more challenging like that's why
I'm trying to do the harder stuff now
before you know it holds me back a
little bit a little bit there for you
yeah I'm not letting life just hold you
down like that and before I go in those
hiked suits making sure I'm as prepared
as possible I try not to take any
medicine whatsoever but ibuprofen I
always carry with me just in case it
starts to hurt drink a lot of water the
week before a hike I make sure there's
no inflammatory foods in my diet like
it's it's about taking the precautions
but yeah it's pretty impressive what I
can do like I can put a 50 pound
backpack on my back even though I have a
bad back and keep walking up a mountain
oh I also have to just take turn
looking up at the beautiful scenery
looking down at my feet just to give my
neck a different angle everyone yeah I
think that's important it's weird we
have all these millions of I don't know
if it's millions but let's say millions
of little micro muscles is what I like
to call them and sometimes they just
don't get a lot of movement I think
about like like think about in your head
like you a nursing home like a grandma
and muumuu
like think about how many I'm stretching
you think about how often I'm so
hilarious I don't set the scene
sometimes I'm just like all of a sudden
grandma I move I'm sorry I'm so visual
too so I was like well I'm there
Mountain MoMA real quick yeah she says
she turns into a muumuu no but just I
think about like think about how often
she moves like how many like her arms
her her micro muscles in her neck and
her toes even flexing I just think of
like when I think of like I wanted to
seem mean to like any old people but
when I think like an old person who like
doesn't move a lot I think of myself and
I think I'm not going to be that I think
my plan is okay I feel like we're gonna
be able to live a lot longer
you know the lot of the research is
they're doing pretty damn well we're
learning about these things that are
causing us inflammation learning about
all these things that we can do to like
help micro muscles all these little
things I just I just imagine when I'm
older I want to be able to move like my
whole body and have access to like all
these different areas and I don't want
to be the old lady in the muumuu I'm
speaking on this probably I'm sorry
Carol but um yeah I think that we kind
of detach ourselves from like we can be
young we could be 25 we could be 30 and
we could say like I'm not gonna be like
that but like if you don't take
precautions to not be like that you know
I'm sure they didn't plan on that either
uh-huh I think it you know and we have
so much more information at our hands
now we have so much more things we can
try we have so much so many people
sharing knowledge yeah I think just
taking control of your life um I do want
to talk word inflammation okay I really
like teaching people about that word
where we can so what foods that give you
information can you tell me about that
do you start discovering like you would
start feeling worse or start for
inflamed in certain ways when you eat
certain foods yeah refined sugar number
one is my number one inflammatory food
and I love it it's something it was
really hard habit to break
and everyone's smile I still give in and
then the next morning I wake up and I am
like I'm like crippled MooMoo granny I
can't do it and it's all the way into my
finger joints and I would go try to lift
weights and I would try to do it like a
normal squat like on land my hips every
every joint was a key and I did that to
me I did it it happens when I eat bread
and with that one I'm not sure if it is
gluten or if if it's preservatives I'm
not sure I haven't quite figured that
out but what I did figure out is when I
eat an autoimmune protocol diet it's
very basic very very basic lots of leafy
greens like paleo sorry yeah it's just
one a little bit one step above paleo so
you're not eating any like pepper or
anything like spicy no potatoes just
kind of potatoes I did come you can a
sweet potatoes it just it's very you do
that for like a month and then you add
back in eggs and see what inflames your
body so it's one of those things instead
of being like oh my god I don't want to
do this it's about being curious because
your body is you're your own science
experiment like anytime that you take a
medication people think that that's
going to cure them and it might or is it
just masking the ailment or is when it
comes to your diet that's something you
do forever you have to eat to stay alive
so what are you eating and is it helping
you feel alive right then I think a lot
of times we are diet and medications is
attacking symptoms mmm I think that we
kind of you know she and I talk about
this often our view on the doctors and
when I say are I'm just generalizing
society like of course not everybody but
we kind of do go to the doctors when
we're hurt and when we're feeling crappy
and we say fix me please and and we
don't take the time to learn about every
single ounce of food we put into our
body right before we went to the doctor
there's reasons why you're feeling this
way not
feeling this way and I want to not feel
this way so give me the thing to make me
not feel it right what's the quickest
fix yeah it's it's do you think it's
like this like just our society's like
need for comfort is you think it's just
kind of a repercussions
it's our society's need for instant
results instant results exact because we
have everything at our fingertips we
want something we can get it right now
but that does not happen with your
health it takes work and it takes you
have to think about it and then it takes
action you can't just think well I want
to lose weight or I want to feel better
I want my neck to hurt less you have to
take action what can I do to get better
and then you have to actually do the
things over and over and over and over
and over and learn about yourself like
that actually didn't feel good when I
ate that I mean my stomach hurt or
didn't feel good when I did that
exercise it hurt my neck I learned that
anytime I put a squat bar on my neck I
don't feel good so I talked to the
doctor about it said see see what what
can I do instead and so I hold weights
on either side of me so that way it's
like pulling my neck and back in the
correct alignment for me instead of
pushing me forward and giving me that
same facial like pinch right it's that
vagus nerve that runs between your c1
and c2 like it's real funky real funky
okay huh that's so interesting when you
when you first started how was the
initial like okay this is an injury this
is like everything in my life needs to
change like my health my whatever what
were some of the I love I love getting
people I love helping put my hand down
and trying to help people off the ground
I think like that first initial if you
can just help people realize that they
can take their you know do you remember
back to that time when oh I can't gotta
make changes like was it was it pretty
hard with diet was it like a slow start
just keep going like was it like I'm
gonna eat healthy and then by its 3 p.m.
you're like eating a bag of Doritos
because that's what I would do but yeah
it is a constant oh ok not so much
anymore it is not so much a constant
struggle because I've already lost
weight I've already felt better someone
know how to do it like I have the tools
to be able to recreate my past
experience but this time I can do it
better
yeah and
so when I first started feeling pain i
associated it with being overweight so
that's when I did the research about
anti-inflammatory foods I didn't get a
diagnosis yet I had actually gone
through that whole process and started
with the keto diet I'm sure you've heard
a lot about the keto diet and I'm sure
that works for so many people but for me
it was so restrictive and my body was
craving a sweet potato and I started to
cry so okay I have under 20 cards and I
just want to bite of this right cuz I'm
one of those people like it's kind of
obsessed with numbers and if I have my
fitness pal make sure I hit it just
right and if I have certain macros like
I'm gonna hit it to be key to gonna do
it right my stubbornness but what was
happening is I was like what the why do
I need to label this why can't I just
eat well and then I lost all the week
because I didn't have any stress no
stress of following a diet specifically
I just ate as much Whole Foods as
possible drink a lot of water I needed
vitamins because I was deficient in some
and moving my body I took the pressure
off myself and the weight also came off
and then once I had lost that weight I
did my neck started to hurt a little bit
more but that's probably because I was
feeling better so I was working more
right but once I did get diagnosed with
that yeah it's it forces you to sit down
like it almost pushes you down like
you've got this thing and I didn't want
it to be me I didn't want it to be what
held me back or became I knew I did any
I can't do that because my neck hurts
yeah that was something I wanted to be
able to say if it was a true thing but I
I feel like the more you this sentence
let me get it
your experiences beliefs your beliefs
are there because of your experiences
and then those same experiences confirm
your beliefs so if I'm sitting there
going I believe that I can't do that
because my neck hurts everything around
me is going to try to confirm that
because we'd like to be right but I was
like I don't want this to be what stops
me and so what do I have to do in order
to be happy or to feel better and then
unfortunately that was you know I'm
going to have to switch my career over
but not right now
it's a ten-year thing or if if it did
get worse obviously I would make the
sacrifice but I wasn't gonna let it
define me
right yeah instead you kind of like
created a balance mm-hmm like like I'm
not going to suffer these things I'm
going to balance them out by going out
and working out and eating better yeah
there's that I have this mentality of
all or nothing I don't really know where
it came from always trying to figure out
the source but I know that it's there
and I have to eat perfect or binge eat I
have to spend big money or save every
penny I have to do a dressed hair or
like I have to do just this thing but
that's not helpful it's really not it's
better to have a balance of like not
viewing things as black or white good or
bad like when it comes to food and
having like treats treats aren't bad too
much just isn't good mm-hmm no like too
much is what gives me inflammation a
piece of like homemade fudge or like
someone brought me a treat that isn't
going to derail me completely right and
then there's not the stress with that
and I don't like coz with the stress I
was tensing up too and so it was causing
more I was really just learning a lot
about my body and what what I was doing
to it by trying to control everything
yeah it's funny cuz I cuz I feel like
I'm still learning about my own body and
I have like now I feel through my yoga
and meditation I feel like so connected
my body but I actually worked out since
I'm 28 when I was in tenth grade I
started working out cuz I was like 140
pounds
and I just wanted to be tough and so I
was like I got to put some size on so
that's like what started me but I never
even after high school from tenth grade
until you know 26 27 I worked out I
would take maybe a week or two off at
the most but I would always work out was
always but like I really wasn't that
healthy like I was just working out I
was pretty much as doing the same thing
like I was going in and I'd do the bicep
curls and I do and I do the bench press
and I did all these things but I didn't
realize that I wasn't like not super
connected to my body in and it's still
something I'm exploring I hope that in
like five years I'm able to talk about
the sentence and be like yeah I did this
because it's something something the
like if you would have asked me four
years ago like do you have a connection
with your body I'd be like yeah the most
powerful connection ever that you don't
even understand but like now I realized
I was an idiot like I and I think that
in what what I'm circling at is I worked
out trying to I used it for like an
aggression thing like trying to get out
my however and I would go there and
that's great but a lot of times I was
just punishing my body like not
connecting to it kind of like a kind of
like that like the body expression of
like looking in the mirror like come on
[__]
that idiot you know like you like those
sort of things like that was kind of
like a lot of my not like super putting
down that fat ID it might be intense but
like you know these things that we kind
of actually say to ourselves when we're
working out like you got to push
yourself but I think that I've learned
to like be soft with myself and be like
come on man I can explore that like you
love your body like it's it's this
different conversation and like I don't
really go to gyms now I have like a fun
workout now and I when I'm like oh I
need to like get some good like a good
workout in or some good miles in I plan
a long run or I plan a high I think that
we look at fitness working out as
something completely separate than
anything else in our life I think that
like people like you who are finding
like more of a holistic like all of this
is health you know all of this is is is
Fitness you know like we can't go into
the gym and just say I punish yourself
and get through it it's like cause
you're in the gym you're also
working on your posture you're working
on your self-confidence you're working
on your self-talk we're working on all
these things that's I think the video
that I posted this morning for wild
wellness was all about that myself loved
herself hey you have a choice break down
the video I didn't watch it
okay so mind you I edited a couple this
morning too so the one that I believe
that was posted this morning was the
self love and self hate and I think I
started it off by saying link if you
wanted to help someone or rather point
someone's behavior out to get them to
change what would work better calling
them out calling them stupid fat idiot
or same like hey I noticed this this is
you know bothering me what can we do to
solve that like which one of those would
actually have a better outcome obvious
yeah the second option and so why don't
we do that to ourselves why do we think
that calling ourselves a stupid idiot in
the gym or like calling I have guilty of
that like grabbing my own fat saying oh
god I'm disgusting I need to go to joke
about it self-deprecating joke awful and
it is something that add to habit to
break and that's like my specialization
with my coaching I'm a habit change
specialist because it's the choices that
we make over and over and over that
become our habits and when we get stuck
in certain habit loops that's when we
notice that we are gaining a little bit
of weight or we are more negative but if
you can break that cycle by making
another choice and another choice and
another choice your habits will shift
and you'll be a different person just in
the gym so if you notice that's what it
is so we're often either completely
oblivious to what we're doing and then
there starts to be this judgmental side
of us that's like oh my god I'm I am
being a jerk to myself that I'm gonna
keep doing it because it obviously works
and then if you can go one step beyond
that and be curious like why am I being
a jerk to myself is there another way is
there a different way yeah there's other
choices to make and they're like but I
don't I don't know what that will bring
me okay so a visualization for this is
say you're walking through a jungle and
there's already a path that's placed you
want to take that because you know how
you know every
about it it's the easiest route but what
if what you actually want is just a
little like bushwhack away you just have
to like clip-clip away at the vines and
everything and blaze a new trail to eat
actually desire that happens with habit
change only at the gym if you're sitting
there being rude to yourself notice it
acknowledge what you're trying to do
you're like oh I'm trying to motivate
myself but there is another way so let's
try it and so that's what I've I had to
do that because I've gained and lost
like 70 pounds a couple times now and
with my neck injury I had to slow down
at the gym I did get you know kind of
sad about it so I was eating differently
even though that doesn't help me but
then I realized what was happening
getting control of it again I started to
be mean to myself I started to notice
and I'm like no look at how cool my body
is anytime my neck starts to flare up
it's giving me a signal yeah look how
cool my body is I like yeah huge mindset
I can I can run I can run more than I
think that I can I can lift more than I
think that I can I can it is so
interesting how if you take an ailment
like your stomach is aching or your
heart is racing and you actually ask why
or what could I do you give yourself
some power back like it's a signal from
your body it's telling you something
like even anxieties so it's so awesome
that more and more people are talking
about anxiety disorders and everything
it's it's a signal from your body
yeah the attention I think that we live
in a with love a diagnosis because it
tells us what's going on but then we
think we need to sit with it okay well
that's that's my presence this is me
yeah but that it's like here's a
diagnosis here's this thing that's
happening here's this thing that you're
feeling it's real look at it realize it
cool now what not how do you make it
look better or what is it telling you is
there things that you need to maybe step
back on and focus on a little more or a
little less or whatever it is you talked
about when you got here you remind me of
something that simon Sinek said about
like excitement versus nervousness like
the feeling the feeling if you separate
the thoughts just empty your thoughts
what
way you can you just feel that feeling
it's super similar if not the exact same
feeling excitement versus nervousness
simon Sinek who's an author that i
really like he talks about this use like
a leadership trainer too he has a bunch
of lectures on youtube if anyone should
check him out it's [__] awesome but
uh he has the thing where he's afraid of
flying he's like very nervous on flights
and so he started sitting on the on the
plane and it starts to get turbulence
and he's like okay
instead of being terrified and having
the cold sweats or whatever it is I'm
just gonna say this is exciting this is
exciting because think about if you're
on a roller coaster you chose to get on
a roller coaster
mmm-hmm you're choosing to be terrified
like it's just all your brains
perception is right it is exciting so in
it sounds silly and it sounds contrived
but if you're a person listening who who
has anxiety who has just like
nervousness like what you know even if
it's just a soft moan even if it's a big
one try just try it saying this is
actually exciting this is exciting and
see like what your what your brain does
and see if your brain like feels this
sort of like excitement so how did you
start like framing your mind in a
different way so like you would feel
nervousness but but you were talking
about when you got here you're you
notice it as excitement now if it was
like 10 years ago and you were feeling
nervous and you had to talk to your ten
years ago so would you tell them like if
this was 10 years ago I what I said no
to doing the podcast cuz it's way
outside my comfort zone like I don't I
don't ever want to put myself in for you
super glad you're here yeah I don't want
to sound foolish ever or like I don't
want to talk about something that I
don't know a hundred percent but in that
case none of us should be talking cuz we
never know anything but ten years ago
and now man the mine
shift that I've had is very significant
I mean I'm 20 to 30 is a huge learning
like age you see um-hmm
so now what I am able to do is separate
myself from my thoughts like I am NOT my
thoughts cuz he everyone so all I've
really should he thought about myself or
maybe another person that's not that
that's not who I am those were just
thoughts they're there they just flow
all day long there they are and every
once in a while like one pops up and we
pay more attention to it and so I was
like why did that thought puppet pop up
in my head actually take the moment to
be like what does that mean is it real
no it's a real thought but is it a real
thing like I acknowledge it and put it
aside if it's important I'll put it over
here and deal with it later or if it's
just like a passing little fleeting fad
like you can go away on to the next
thing
that's definitely I do that a lot now
it's just being able to like step
outside and observe yourself your
thoughts your actions and does that
align with where you want to be we all
have pasts guys pasts are things we
don't
some people are perfect you know but
some of us have are familiar yeah I've
I've done some things I'm not proud of
and I can I necessarily make up for
those things no but I can change my the
way that I do everything mm-hmm and to
me like it does help me feel better
about everything that I've gone through
everything that I've done it led me to
right where I'm at and from this point
that's when I have the power to make the
choices that align with the life that I
see for myself right I love that
everyone has that power yeah that uh
that's what I keep trying to like point
out here is is that moment when you're
like you're on the trail and you're
going on the trail then when you notice
you're on the trail that right there the
noticing it's all it takes and noticing
like okay I'm on this trail like what am
i you know like what is this trail do I
want to go into the bushes over here do
I want to go check those out like you
can stop running on the trail for a dang
second and this is a metaphor not talk
about hiking on sudden but
yeah yeah that that I think that Joe
Rogan has this thing I watched a lot of
like motivational YouTube videos a lot
of times I wake up and my depression
tries to strangle me a little bit and so
the first thing I do is like nope ain't
happenin today and so I put some like
motivational stuff on yeah and again
later just has a side note again later I
look at like okay it seems that maybe I
was having some problems with sleep it's
happening to maybe see maybe nightmares
let's look at that maybe I was eating
something wrong before bed it was kind
of triggering these whatever so I get
curious yeah so that's definitely thing
but but a the when I wake up in the
morning and put on these motivational
videos there's one that I listen to Joe
Rogan's voice actually and these people
edit it together essentially they show
have you seen the movie limitless with
Bradley Cooper yeah he take it's
essentially they show him at the
beginning moving he's like imagine this
is your superhero movie right now this
is your life today is the first opening
scene and you're the piece of [__]
before it gets his [__] together you're
that you know and you know don't call
yourself piece of [__] but if that's
what you need that day to like I need to
change you you see yourself as like the
loser like you don't have a lot of money
and your your apartments dirty you know
this is like the scene they paint and
and then you you just kind of like I'll
send you a Isaac damn it you know like I
gotta do something different like I
gotta get I have to walk on my hero's
journey here I guess like you know like
we've seen all these movies where like
at the beginning where the people just
weren't fully there we've seen Thor
we've seen you know I think like well
Captain America has been awesome all the
time but there's all these superheroes
all these people in these movies who at
the beginning they were just not proud
of themselves and maybe they did things
that they didn't want it like all they
didn't believe in and now they're
punishing himself for it but what you
can do is you can wake up today Monday
Tuesday Wednesday Thursday Friday
Saturday or Sunday whatever day it is
you can say I'm done with that yeah I'm
I'm not doing that you know and I think
that like that that is one of the most
powerful things that like a human can
hear sometimes is like dude whatever
happened yesterday you can you can't
rewind time unless you know how to build
like a time machine that's pretty
intense but I think it's a great thing
and I think it's empowering you know and
it's given me a lot of power because I I
have a lot of the saint-like self hate
thoughts and a lot of self shame a lot
of guilt a lot of a lot of things that
everybody has you know in
but but what I would I say is I come out
here and I say I'm not perfect and I
haven't always been and I didn't expect
you to be but like you can say today is
the first day of your heroes movie and
you could start getting to work you know
you could start clean one pan and you
know if you have a sink full of dishes
clean one pan you know whatever you got
to do make that choice yeah I am pretty
open and honest about like my depression
as well and that's when it got really
really really bad and I was having the
suicidal thoughts and everything but
what I realized then is it is about much
it's about twice again like I there was
too much to live for
and too many people that would have been
affected so I I felt like I wasn't going
to make that choice so since I'm not
what choices could I make to help build
me back up and I was on a really long
drive when I was at my lowest point but
when I got to my destination that's when
I went to the grocery store I got the
proper foods I got water I sat down and
I started writing I wrote this is where
like action comes into play and that is
so important to sit there and be curious
like why do I feel this way not just
repeating I'm broken I'm sad I can't do
this like that that constant repetition
you start to truly it's it's your
identity you believe it it's it is your
belief it is your deserve it yeah yeah
oh the second part of that quote that I
said where your beliefs in your
experiences coexisting yeah all
experiences are available at all times
oh I love that that's not on your wall
yeah I definitely don't know because we
forget we forget that all experiences
are available at all times if you are on
your rock bottom you'll have to stay
there you can feel those things but then
you can also self analyze and that's
what I did on a piece of paper I wrote
down every single thing that was
overwhelming to me that I felt that I
had failed at that I just um
like a bad list almost I just needed to
get it out on paper and look at it and
like that doesn't seem very constructive
but the next part is on the flip side of
the paper I literally wrote what to do
about it
each bullet point I found a solution for
and then
from that day which was only that was
last May it was kind of like after the
diagnosis and that it came there was a
lot more to the diagnosis and just being
told that it's like family stuff but
when I was at my absolute low point that
was the only way that I could try to get
better I was like okay what I'm doing is
not working anymore what could I do
different and that's when I made that
list not every day I looked at the I
looked at all the things and then I
would flip the paper over and what could
I do about it
and I started to do those things and
pretty soon on the the bad side started
getting crossed off because they were
non-existent who that's the crazy that
that's something that when that when you
realize like oh shoot like so I'm in two
weeks or it's been two months or
whatever and like I actually don't do
that thing anymore like I actually don't
have that far I like something that you
literally two months ago or two weeks
ago whatever it was before you wrote it
down like that's your identity like
that's a daily thought like sometimes
self-hate thought you're not worthy
thought whatever it may be or like just
trying to conceptualize it yeah it's
it's crazy to see that you can unwind
that I had a thing that I wrote that was
uh like it was essentially like a dream
list it was like a one day I want to
like do this think this is my perfect
day and it was like a it was like a pipe
dream when I wrote it and I actually had
put it up on the wall and I had so much
[__] on the wall that I think a bunch of
those thoughts and a few months later I
went back through in it it was like a
weird moment like before I went to bed
I'd grabbed it off the wall I didn't
even plan on it and I was just like
glancing at it I don't even know like
what led me to do this you know I had
this like she's just softening in my
whole body I was reading it just started
bawling I was like oh my god I did all
these things today and like it was it
was down to silly things for me I was
like you know like record a podcast with
this / or she knows something like even
just a little goals but also mental
things I think I gotta ask you something
do you think that writing is magic
because I think that writing is actual
magic yeah what okay so I was writing
Randall letters love letters huh and
what would happen is any time we'd have
like a disagreement or something I went
to sleep I would take to writing and
then be
how's my hand would just move very
quickly and I would just pour it onto
the paper I actually learned a lot about
myself yeah and helped me figure out
issues and then I feel like putting pen
to paper it it's your reality what I was
doing was my reality it was taking all
my thoughts and putting on paper and I
could actually read it back to myself
like ah do I like the story that I'm
creating for myself well no we have the
option to create a different one how do
you the how do you I'm just trying to
think of like people who write it down
and they're like okay what does this do
I'm trying how do you separate how do
you okay so you write something down I'm
just trying to think I feel like when I
would write something down you almost
you separate yourself it's almost like
that's not me
or something like it's almost like this
weird comment it's like a conversation
with yourself they have to be willing to
partake and when you're right right it's
like how did you conceptualize like you
write it down and then how do you not
turn that into like self-hate again
because a lot of times I would write
down go you're out of these things and
then I look at me like you're
daydreaming fool you're about the good
stuff that you want to do yeah do you
ever have anything like that like you
write it down like good cuz I always sit
like on this podcast I preach like write
it down and it's magic right but
sometimes you write it down you don't
really like some some people just don't
have the self-love to write it and then
I guess see it as something they can
change yeah remote coaching standpoint
if someone says like I wrote down this
list and I just makes me feel stupid
like I'll never accomplish it blah blah
blah I would say like what is what is
that trying to teach you what could you
learn from that like what would having
those things do for you and then we
start talking about the more positive
things that it could bring or every once
in a while someone has like an ecology
issue where let's I'm gonna go always
back to weight loss it's like the
easiest thing for me to talk about right
now but if it's like weight loss or like
I want to wear a bikini at the beach I
want to not get the belt extender on the
airplane I want to do these things like
but I'll never do that I never could
like okay and we talk about what would
having those things do for them and
bring them joy and comfort
like they'd be in family pictures and we
find the why but every once awhile that
why is because their whole family is
overweight and if they lost the weight
they wouldn't fit in anymore
or like say that when it comes to diet
or a family event they're like well I
have to eat those mashed potatoes why
and then we work through a series of
questions that gets it to like well I
don't want to hurt my auntie's feelings
because she's always made those for me
and that's how we connect so it's just
it's kind of like being exported with
yourself and your mind and there's
always a reason why there's something
holding you back we just had to figure
out what it is yeah and I think keeping
going and diving into it I mean honestly
even just like still riding a lot of
times you can almost figure that stuff
out for yourself but I think it's cool
that you're able to offer people like
okay that's fine we can grow that that's
what's going on now let's let's take a
look at it how do you work with people
and even in your own life when it comes
to the family dynamics is is pretty like
like what wanting change like I have so
it's difficult to be like okay I'm on
this serious diet like I've been on you
know salmon whole xxx right I'm eating
this certain way and then you go to a
family dinner and it really is like this
I'm not gonna paint every like older
person but like everybody's mom
everybody's aunt is kind of a jerk about
it I think it seems like it's very
difficult like you almost don't want
like make it a big deal you would rather
just say no to the mashed potatoes but
it seems like this big old thing
dealing with family not at first
accepting your change oh do you have any
I think that's a big one
yeah own it you have to own it if it's
your truth own it and then it becomes
like if they're gonna make fun of it
doesn't matter it's what you're doing
and if they're not supporting you it
doesn't mean that they don't love you it
just means that they're not comfortable
doing it yet and they don't have to it's
not their journey it's yours it's your
decision do what you want and come
prepared and if that means coming
prepared with your own whole thirty meal
cool or bring something whole 30-ish for
the family to share but also come
prepared for other people's shitty
comments because they're gonna be there
they just are any time that someone
changes a part of themselves there's
some observer or
that's used to you fitting in the box
that they put you in so if you step out
of it I'm gonna change I'm gonna do
these things it makes sometimes it makes
other people uncomfortable but it
doesn't they're uncomfortable my
favorite saying to is get comfortable
with being uncomfortable because that if
your family member is uncomfortable and
starts attacking you that makes you feel
weird about the way they feel but you're
ignoring you're ignoring your own self
you're ignoring your own feelings
because you're trying to keep them
comfortable like so sit there for a
second just like all they're upset I'm
not eating how they want me to eat
that's an interesting observation but my
goals are this and I'm gonna stick to my
food yeah this is my this is my truth
this is what I'm doing yeah I think it's
hard with with families you know
families are always something that like
I have a different weird family dynamic
but I imagine that for other people who
are like very close to their family like
if you do have your aunt's famous mashed
potatoes all the time like there is
literally probably like at first she's
gonna get generally I kind of upset if
you're not eating the mashed potatoes
you know I think that but when you could
open up these conversations and when you
could be Stern with yourself I think
that when you start seeing yourself as
an adult in your family when you start
saying like if I just walked up to your
house I didn't know any of you people
you would respect me as a grown man and
woman but like for some reason I seem to
be allowing myself to slip into this
fifteen-year-old version of myself just
because we came home on the holiday oh
yeah oh yeah we do that in so many ways
but I think that um you know with family
when you really start you know not being
mean but just being Stern just being
like owning it like you setting
boundaries yeah do you find or do you
have in any of the people that you've
that you've also taught these things to
do you find that their families start
coming around eventually or where do you
what do you think certain family members
but it's also important to remember that
you can't let other people be the main
influence to your own happiness because
if you did that you'd never be happy
because you'd spend all your time trying
to make sure everyone else was happy too
pleaser yeah and I know that I know that
personally and with the clients I hear
it a lot absolutely whether it's the
hair
dressing on the coaching and that's just
it's not a fun place to be or you're
waiting for something else to be happy
that's a big one too is my favorite
question to ask people is like what do
you want as people are chronically
misunderstood and their people don't
listen we listen to respond we don't
listen to understand and so by asking
someone like what do you want there they
open up big time and then from there
we'll talk about the family dynamics and
like what they can foresee being an
issue and let's go back to antes
potato's communication as everything if
you're that close to that aunt that you
feel like you need to eat the potatoes
to make her happy why can't you have a
conversation saying like hey auntie like
I got diagnosed with heart disease
I can't that kind of stuff anymore would
it be okay if I brought an alternative
or would it be okay if I just didn't put
it on my plate would you understand
right maybe pull them to the side
roast granny yeah Carole is always there
you know what's funny is my my one of my
she's she's since passed but I actually
have a grandma her name was Carol and
for some reason like every time I'm
somehow I'm just making fun of an old
lady on this podcast I just named her
Carole in my head I feel like I
mentioned Carole she's grandma's name is
Carole - oh sorry I'm just talking about
her movement so we have make sure we
cover all of our bases here I love
jumping around in casual conversation
but I always want to make sure that we
that we bring it back to like what
you're what you're trying to tell the
world here I know there's so many
different like [__] is it faucets
Bassets
yeah I was gonna go with faucets well no
there's so many faucets out there so
many sinks faucets sinks Fosters and so
that's yeah there's different avenues
and there's so many especially when
you're in the beginning stages of really
learning stuff there's so much
interesting knowledge that you want to
share with the world and everything so
it is hard to like pinpoint it down
bring it down to a niche of some sort
and that's
at the end of the day that's why what I
do is labeled like have it change
because I want to be able to remind
people that they do have control of
their life if you don't like your
relationship we can work together to get
you to where you want to be like whether
it's that's fixing the relationship
we're trying to like mend things or to
get out of it or if you don't like your
job is there conversation that needs to
happen with your boss or like your
coworker surroundings or do we need to
get you set up for a different career
opportunity it's any mm every every
single person seems to have something so
vastly like different but it all stems
around making choices like the right
choices instead of the ones that were
used to making are like normal habits
it's almost like it's this thing where
you realize you have choices mm-hmm
right like we go our whole life just
doing the same things and we're like
find sucks when that happens we don't
realize it at some point you can just
put a wedge in it and be like I'm gonna
do this now like just change it up and
sometimes people are too scared to
change it up and that's why we offer the
let's see what happens you can always
come back to your old behaviors but why
not see what happens do you like do you
like that experience okay now let's try
something more and see what happens how
was that it just sets up like little
tiny baby steps to make people more
comfortable with the shift because
that's the the black and white mentality
sometimes is like just completely
shutting a door and running into a
different direction like that's not
always yeah for everybody you got to be
able to take a look at it mm-hmm I think
that I think a lot of people what's your
experience with I use the word mental
health with my podcast it's a mental
health podcast in sometimes I have a
little fear that that it gets thrown
into like Oh only if you have severe
depression you want to kill yourself
should you listen to my podcast like or
like mental health is something that
people it's either a fad that they that
they get into they think or they think
that it's a something that's like when I
get to where I need it that's where all
but I think that mental health is
something that with this crazy crazy
world the way that we're living as
humans the way that our minds work
were understanding our minds in
different new ways were becoming aware
of many things that 50 years ago humans
just weren't aware of I think that
mental health is or everybody I think
that what's your experience with people
who I'm trying to word it people who
don't want help but I I'm just thinking
of people who avoid things like this
conversations like this because they're
doing just fine you know what I mean
like like and not that everybody like I
think everybody could be better that's
always a cool thing you know but but I
think a lot of times people are
suffering their own self without
realizing it yeah yeah mental health
does have some sort of like stigma to it
people it's becoming more and more like
socially I don't want to use the word
acceptable but people have a better
understanding of what it means because
people are being honest about it and
yeah there is that like stigma behind it
and sometimes it is a push with clients
to get them to open up about their
thought processes but that's when I just
kind of like veer in a different way and
we start talking about physical health
or like where they're at spiritually or
financially just kind of helping people
open up a little bit and then that often
turns into the way that they're thinking
about stuff and then I just say like oh
this is an opportunity to talk about the
mental health part of it and if they
recoil a little bit I just pause I let
them sit there on their own discomfort
and then normally they softened a
hundred percent of the time so far
they'd be just softened it mean like
okay tell me more tell me okay what do I
do
what what are my options as even though
they're not able to fully understand how
to make options for themselves they at
least are starting to understand that
they're there yeah yeah I think that's
like one of the biggest things is
realizing that they're there yeah like
like hey you said you you started riding
like just figuring it out you just sat
down started writing I mean I like when
I was just super bummed like when I
first started writing on this wall and
that was kind of how it was it was just
like too many nights of coming home and
just falling on the floor crying this
time I was like let's stick here
crisscross applesauce with a sharpie
my hand and figure out what the hell I'm
thinking yeah you know wrote it down and
you were doing something creative so you
are breaking your cycles yeah
breaking cycles have you how do you
what's your I might jump into like to to
spiritual or or to metaphysical here but
what's your what your thoughts on like
breaking family cycles my guy I have I
got
following my history like of my family
my family tree like and there's just
like depression suicide mental
breakdowns like it's just on both sides
it's everywhere and I had a few homies
over last night or like last week we had
a few beers we had a we had a podcast
and we were started talking we got on
this page of like all three of us in
this room had like very similar
experiences when we were young like we
started talking about those and we we
kind of had this moment of pride where
we're like you know what we're [__]
breaking that though like we're not like
yeah our dads did that to us yeah yeah
our family had that happened but but
dang guys like we're in this room
breaking that cycle in a lot of times
that there's books and there's all these
things of like breaking the
transdimensional curse or whatever I'm
using words like the breaking a family
curse essentially like you have these
things like my family has always been
like this and I was taught how to be
like this since I was 15 or whatever but
we're discovering now like we can start
changing and making our own choices like
okay that was how it was for my family
for my lineage my DNA but like that's
not how it's gonna be if when I have
kids absolutely you know absolutely how
you think that's like a thing like just
breaking those curses lisk
right yeah it's a definite finger yes me
and my cousin we sit down and we talk
about this often cuz we even though we
have different sets of parents it's from
the same upbringing and we both went
through situations that we didn't know
each other went through even though
we're only a couple years apart because
there's like the family secrets do and
so part of being able to break those
cycles is to recognize that they're
there in the first place because do you
ever I mean as as a human and you get
worked up you ever end up staying
thing that you wish that you didn't say
yeah but you don't want to be wrong so
you're gonna stand there and be right
yeah you like bury yourself you have
yourself from that wrong thing you said
yeah
or you just you just keep pushing
pushing pushing link that's that's a
family thing for me and yeah it takes a
lot of effort to break the cycle but it
is possible and that's one of those
things about being able to step outside
yourself and ask like was that the best
reaction or actually pay attention to
how it affected the person that you're
talking to yeah like oh I saw that that
hurt them like crap that might have been
my intention but I don't like how it
feels that's an opportunity for you to
shut your mouth for one second sit there
in that feeling and then make a choice
to correct it right that's the first
step I agree I think it just keeps
everything we've been saying just come
back to like this noticing them that
awareness like that moment of like give
yourself a second ya notice it
acknowledge it and then if you feel like
it's not suiting you anymore change it
if you don't know how reach out for help
or do the research on the internet or
ask a friend or ask the person that
you're talking to I have to do that
because I was raised in a really rigid
home so I have those rigid habits of my
own and I would didn't I wasn't allowed
to make a lot of choices growing up
they're made for me and so as an adult
when I make one that's it no one can
change my mind so all I am doing is
repeating the cycle so now when I even
though it's my habit to be that way and
I feel like I can't possibly have a
conversation I have to be so like this
is what I want this is my choice you
can't tell me not to do it or change my
mind in any way I'm I see the reaction
on my husband's face and and then I'm
like okay can I try that again and
that's what breaks a cycle it's just by
simply asking like can I try that again
in how does he does he leave your room
for these absolutely that the receiving
side is a huge thing like if you're on
the other side of someone like clearly
like you love this person and they're
just a little frustrated they're trying
to figure out what they think and you
know sometimes we say things we don't
mean sometimes we're that kind of mean
when we say it or whatever
argument or something but I love that
he's like willing to like allow you to
like the room to say like alright yeah
let let's redo that
yeah he's granted me so much room to
grow as a person whereas my past
relationship not so much you know this
is it's so nice having a partner that's
always trying to be better themselves
too so we do give each other that
leniency to grow and sometimes one of us
is sitting there while the other person
is like doing growth and then we're not
completely on the same level but then we
sit down and talk about that too and I
don't know it's all about communication
and recognising what's going on and then
just when it comes to those family
cycles and stuff if you don't like how
things are if you don't like how it
feels you can change it you can get up
you can stand up and you can do
something differently yeah and habits
are hard to break sometimes I just come
out of your mouth but you could say I'm
sorry that was
that's something I'm trying to change
right can I try to word that differently
I think that when you're honest about
stuff like that like it's like this
podcast for example I get like sometimes
I put my foot in my mouth and I kind of
say the wrong thing right like for some
reason I seem to be mixing up I always
mix up the word serotonin and dopamine
and oxytocin and I say that incorrectly
but like I'll listen back and sometimes
we're so afraid of saying the wrong
thing because because do you think it's
because our world our media are like
whatever has always been like remember
this person said this thing 25 years ago
they said there's a little sentence and
now they don't replay the club yeah but
I think that we're gonna start realizing
that every one of us has said some
stupid [__] once or twice or 50 times or
50 times a day you know we're not we're
not simply outwards because when you ask
somebody like oh what did you mean and
you just give them a little bit of room
fulling that's it - if the if you're
standing there and you're not quite sure
what the other person means ask right
don't assume that you know what someone
is trying to say if it's not completely
clear right ask questions be curious
yeah I have conversations gosh in in
being able to ask questions so this is
another we're shifting from that
position from that person the receiving
end so someone is talking like asking
questions okay you don't understand it
you're on the receiving end
someone's trying to explain to you
you're a little
you're like what are you trying to say
here you're on the receiving end of this
conversation listener
I think realizing that a lot of us have
places that we're coming from we have
pre opposed what's the word I'm looking
for when a homeless man walks up to you
this is gonna be a stretch but hang with
me
homeless man walks up to you versus when
your mom walks up to you think about
your body language so when a homeless
man wants up you're like not totally
comfortable you know maybe he like
doesn't give the appearance that he's
well-kept that he's that he's well
saying like you know these are obvious
things and not saying it's a judgement
on the homeless man but we have yeah we
have areas that we come with so when
we're talking to the homeless man it is
going to be a different side of our like
mine like a different conversation a
different place we're sitting in than it
is if our mom's talking to us you know
like there's or someone that you love
that you're talking to you're going to
leave them so much room because you're
like I know you so well I know that you
don't mean to hurt me with what you're
saying but a lot of times when it's a
homeless person they walk up to you and
they say hey this thing um automatically
assume whatever they're saying is just
selfish or it's whatever you don't you
don't leave them the same room as
someone you love as you're judging them
yeah it's an immediate judgment like oh
yeah I think we have different judgments
on different types of people different
situations in our life I had a small
video on my youtube that was picking up
a piece of trash and it was like the way
that I in the piece of trash was a
coffee cup the way that I held would
hold a coffee cup that's mine is warm
and I want my fingers to really feel it
and I love it and I hold it close to my
body but when I picked up a piece of
trash in this YouTube video this is also
just I want to tell everybody I think
I'm trash but but I picked up the trash
and I was holding with two fingers and I
was it wasn't fully touching it cuz if
someone is garbage right but it's a
coffee cup it's the exact same thing
that if I purchased it with my own money
I'd be holding it close to my heart
give me gripping it and be feeling the
warmth of the coffee but when we pick up
a piece of trash we're kind of like we'd
go hold away I think that we treat
conversations like this sometimes we
can't we come to the conversation not
assuming the other person's trash but
we're kind of holding them with two
fingers kind of outwards like like
you're saying this thing
and if it starts to make sense now like
that's kind of like the way we would
treat a homeless person but when it's
your cup of coffee it's someone you love
you give them the grace you give them
the room that they need to tell you like
should I didn't mean to say that all
right I mean the here's my intention
yeah some people are the opposite do
because when it's family you know them
so you can be more aggressive or more
assertive and then they're just supposed
to deal with it or if it was a stranger
you might have more compassion because
you don't want to be seen in a certain
way we do flip that all yeahit's that's
in every situation we ever talk about
there is multiple perspectives to have
but it's not interesting yeah so that's
when it's just about being curious when
you feel yourself have any kind of
emotion whether it's um scared of a bear
or you're fearful or like questioning
why a homeless person would be like
approaching you or your mom walks in the
room lovingly like no matter what it is
if you're just curious just if you feel
yourself feel a thing just get curious
about what it means right because so
many so many times we can paint
ourselves into these corners of not of
thinking they mean this thing or
thinking they're assuming this but it's
like okay wait I know that you're you're
a good person you don't mean me harm
with what you're saying it seems like
what you just said was a little intense
like what like let them have some room
to reword it if they want to you know
yes
and that comes full circle with they're
repeating the family stuff do is like
often with your family or comfortable to
act like a little [__] sometimes
sometimes total brat yeah and what about
with your loved ones like is it okay to
vent your whole day to them mm-hmm and
to take it out on them
right no that's a good one that's a good
one so do you ever do that like when you
had a bad day you just want to like get
a hold your loved one and just tell them
everything about it and just like the
because there's a balance of just having
someone that you can share at all times
I think Facebook does this for us when
as soon as something bad happens we have
a place that we can go vent about that
bad thing the both of my career fields
whether it's hairdressing in their
coaching there's confidentiality behind
that so like yes the day could weigh
very heavy on me but I can't repeat it
so if I need to get it out there like to
my husband I will say
ask me any questions do not ask me who
it is just listen to this okay um if the
wait got too heavy on my back but then
there's another little tidbit a little
tidbit for you guys if you are in a
career field where you carry a lot of
weight from other people's stories or if
like you're around certain people that
steal your energy or just add a lot to
your plate um I don't remember who came
up with this but the threshold theory so
when I was in the salon and I would get
that information at the end of the day I
would flip off the light switch and then
I would walk through a threshold I'd
leave that [__] inside the salon door
and shut it because I'm that's my job I
chose this I it's a it's a blessing that
people open up to me and it's not a
burden it just I'm in empathetic yeah so
I carry it but that's my role during a
work hour then I'm a wife like then
you're a mom and you're a husband when
you walk through your home door so if
you like visually you're walking through
a threshold be a better person be a
better spouse step into those shoes like
be able to leave it at the door so
that's definitely something that had to
work on because um if I were to tell
someone the things that I hear then they
have to carry it too and it's not their
job they're not trained to be able to
separate that because there's a
compassion but it's slightly
disconnected I don't have to feel your
pain I just have to listen to it and as
a professional I'm able to do that it
helps it so other people can tell their
full story and be completely heard is
someone else isn't trying to feel it for
them I'm here to listen I kind of as
you're talking about I was kind of
envisioning like a like a monk like say
you're talking to a monk I feel like
you'd be so calm you're just cause these
things happened and this thing happened
he's just sitting they may be so comic
he would take that from you just fine
but then he would he wouldn't like push
it back out in that same way to anybody
else in his own way of stories he would
just you would calmly handle that and he
would you would I don't know amicably
like allow you to release it I guess hmm
I think that's super incredible yeah
when people open up about stuff it's I'm
just there to hold the space and then
they tell me what they want or what it
would do for them I get to remind them
why they are they sat down on my chair
in the first place I think remind people
of their why so if they spill their guts
to me and I sit there like a monk calm I
just hold on to all the information
sometimes I jot it down to have it for
later and often those things come up
again and I'm able to remind them like
either why they happened or what we can
do to prevent them in the future future
future or sometimes it's the things that
they are crying about it's with the most
desire I can pull that out too so it's
like yeah so I'll handle all the things
that you say with care but I'm also
going to like file it just in case right
I like that that's good and I really
like the part where you said you turn
off the lights and that's like your
threshold you walk through so that's
kind of like when I say you give things
power that's like you made like this
like ritual so for this if I'm
understanding right you're like at the
end of the day like cool okay I'm
turning this off I have whatever is
coming through my head I just heard
about Cynthia's divorce and I just heard
about you know Claudia's car broke down
and like all these things and so when
you walk through that threshold it's
like this moment you give yourself this
I'm walking from this door to this door
in the dark and you're just like letting
it and keeping this here like you're so
you're kind of what's what's uh I love
that I just I just wonder how can we
empower other people to insert parts
like that into their life like like I'm
because I think I do have when I walk in
here in the morning I say good morning
junkyard love every morning I think that
that's my I think that that's actually a
my like whatever like I said sometimes
I'm going through I wake up and
sometimes my mornings just aren't so
great right away I got to kind of insert
my own stuff but I do have that good
morning John Carroll of is what I say
every morning when I walked on it I
think that's kind of a you're like
blessing your space yeah you're
acknowledging and like thinking it like
good morning I think that's important
what if people did that to themselves
what do people do that to themselves and
even if they don't own their own
business their own whatever like I think
just walking like you have co-workers
you work at another salon II work at
somewhere else with other people like
say it under your breath like you know
give yourself that power when you walk
in or even looking in the mirror and
doing it that is an interesting exercise
tell me about me or work have you done
me
work yeah here's the simplest exercise
for people to try look in the mirror
look yourself like in the eye the best
that you can and tell yourself you like
say I love you can't can you do it so
many people cannot yeah I couldn't no it
feels weird I'm like I feel stupid I'm
not doing that
it feels good president love myself then
it was so it was such a bizarre exercise
and it took a long time for me to be
able to look in the mirror and start
pointing out the things I loved and some
of the things that I hate yeah I have a
army wipe my nose here but I have a I
have a friend Nate he talks about how he
used to actually get ready in the dark
he's like a motivational speaker now and
stuff but he talks about how he hated
himself so much and he he didn't even
realize he was doing it or why he was
doing it he just thought like I just
don't turn the lights on in the morning
he hated looking at himself in the
morning because he was ashamed of who he
was and what he was doing but he then
started like realizing he was doing it
started looking in the mirror and then
like it's hard it's really hard and
again it feels weird right it feels like
they can contrive and neck what am i
doing like if somebody walked into this
room I would be so embarrassed but like
actually has power look yourself in here
like yeah I mean Nate told me you know
it's got power for him what what do you
say it so like you ever had like
conversations with yourself in the
mirror like let's see yeah yeah I it's
mostly if I find myself being the
opposite of what I'm trying to be I'll
make myself say out loud the opposite of
what I am initially thinking like if I'm
looking in the mirror and I just like I
don't know have discussed happening then
I will notice that and then stand there
and be like okay I am NOT disgusting I
am awesome
I think I have beautiful eyes like just
start it feels weird even saying it out
loud on podcast because it feels vain in
some way I'm like no it's self love it's
it why is it so easy for us to tear each
other or ourselves apart and then it's
really hard to give compliments to
ourselves or to take a compliment you
know that too I mean that's something
that I'm still I like shame that I'm we
talked about a lot lately I I closed off
receiving like a like so many people
message me and are like talk to me and
and just say thanks for the podcast and
thanks for like whatever and like I have
to make sure now and it's good and I'm
better at it and and I really like it
now but I used to like literally I would
just the instant thing I would get these
texts or whatever and I would just like
I need to respond to them so they like
feel important like I literally just
reflect as soon as I like deflect it and
not actually be like gosh you know what
Jake like you're doing good man like or
you know now I like I'll show Shaylee
and I'm like hey babe check this out and
she goes oh and I go oh and we just like
hug each other and I'm just you know
we're excited for where we're at but I
think you got to give yourself those
like things right yes um point out your
accomplishments yeah write them down
yes I so there's another method and
without reviewing my notes I don't ever
remember like who originally thought
these things up but you know how like
productivity is often a list and we
check it off a to-do list
and as we go through that list we start
to feel a little bit better as we you
know tink it off the list but if we
don't complete it we feel like absolute
garbage we beat ourselves up like oh we
didn't manage our time correctly all
that we start picking the day apart I'm
a list making mofo yeah that's how I
feel good it started to really control
my attitude so then I heard this thing
called it two dullest or if I'm feeling
unproductive and then I didn't
accomplish anything or maybe there's 15
things on my list and I only got a
couple done a to-do list is the opposite
like I'm retraining my brain to have a
different outlook and so what I did that
day he's all written down and then I sit
there and acknowledge it right and
lately with the gym - I remember what my
my body could do ten years ago and so as
I'm like running or doing something I
can feel myself comparing and despairing
to my old habits like my old self what
it look like what I could do and I
noticed that so then in a note section
of my fellow night literally says
accomplishments and it says I ran five
minutes straight I lifted this like I
showed up today and I didn't want to I
made this choice and any time I start to
get down at myself I'm actually no way
these things and I let myself feel the
positivity
I let myself celebrate me instead of
compare right it's awesome I think
that's so good you know we live in this
I think a lot of times people we get
afraid of like Tooting our own horn
because there's like this ego like like
show off sort of thing that we're always
so afraid of being like we're always
like oh I don't want to hype myself up
because I don't want people think I'm
cocky or whatever but it's like dude you
- you should be cocky right yeah you
should be talking to yourself like you
you're awesome like you did those things
today and sometimes that like writing
something down like so say if even I'm
listening you may do this do you ever
write anything down just so you can
cross it off immediately
yes yeah that's like the best instant
because I already did it yeah we got a
look at how our brains work like
listener if you've ever written a list
and you compliment it off that felt good
as [__] didn't it yeah exactly give
yourself that you probably did maybe you
maybe you like didn't hit all your goals
today maybe it was just kind of a
half-assed day or maybe you're just
feeling like I didn't do anything today
I think that you'll find if you do if
you do our vector said just like write
that down what did you do today list or
today so even if there's nothing on the
to DA list like you said you wake up the
morning you have this full list of
things you're gonna do and then
something happen and you just like sit
on the couch it would be really easy to
turn around and be like wow I really
messed up this day or did you need a day
off what's the positive intention behind
you not being able to get off the couch
today let's honor that you needed a rest
day you had a crazy day at work like
maybe you just had a fight with somebody
or like maybe your loss is the weirdest
thing on the planet
something good you know someone could
pass away or you can you know go through
something like that and then one year
later you just find yourself sitting on
the couch sobbing about it what's the
positive intention behind sitting on the
couch not accomplishing anything there's
always a reason yeah maybe you just
needed to feel that yeah maybe it's yeah
a lot of our do you think that do you
think there's a lot of stuff that we
we don't slow down enough to give
ourselves time to process it someone
asked me how I am I say I'm busy is
because if I don't stay busy and I'm
slow for a minute tears will just stream
down my face cuz there was so much I
wasn't dealing with right and yeah but I
think when you find little areas of your
life like okay I can deal with this part
right now feelings drink for this and
think sometimes that's what that's what
life is
yeah you got to almost build your
resilience it's like I know I got to
handle that [__] I got to be resilient
before I handle it so let's like get
there well that's something that happens
to when people are feeling that they
should honor the sadness so that they're
going through something and they're like
I'll deal with it later okay you can do
that but then it might start to pop up
in other areas of your body like are you
are you having a breakout or like with
me is my neck hurting more because I'm
being tense are is your bowels are they
acting up like the stress the emotions
you don't handle it it's gonna show up
in other areas of your life yeah I think
I'm a joy not a majority I don't know
that's a broad thing but like me and
stomach pain stomach issues guessed the
gas pains like holy crap it's so related
to our mental health the body keeps
score have you read that book that's a
book called the body keeps us going over
there and I'm like I was in well yes
actually you could totally Monica Marley
I started it I haven't totally gotten
through it it's super good so far but I
did do the thing where I like watched
interviews about it and I read about an
unblinking and so in my head I think
that I've read it but I feel like I
didn't but no yeah the body keeps a
score that's like a little bit more in
depth but our body really does hold on
to trauma something that meditation
teaches me is if the the I don't know
the better at meditation is a weird
sentence to say but the better I get at
meditation the the further I progress in
my path in my stages man I realized that
like I could be sitting there my
meditations and I'm thinking a thought
not realizing I'm thinking it right
you're lost in thought ball crap and you
remember like okay I'm meditating
back to the back to the attention here
but at that moment you've literally
feel like your your left shoulder blade
kind of dropped down a little bit like
it's these weird sort of things and I
can't wait to you know in the coming
years with like my riding in my research
I really hope to conceptualize this to
like really help people out with this
because I think it's crazy important I'm
at the beginning just experiencing it
myself yeah it's so do you ever have any
for one are you meditator or do you know
oh this is how much time do we have now
okay so I did try meditation I'm always
always always seeking calm and quiet and
where I can collect my thoughts because
my head is chaos so I try to combat that
with calm and through counseling and
different coaching methods and different
retreats and stuff it always kept coming
back to the person that was giving me
instruction when I would say oh yeah I
just like to sit in my quiet time and
like sit in my meditation pillow have my
salt lamp all the things like just try
to breathe into that every single person
was like why don't you dance why don't
you try something else well and I'm
stubborn so I was like no I'm just not
good enough at meditation and they're
like well how's it working for you way
to call me call me only it works
sometimes gave like okay well what would
it feel like to try something else my
god feel resistance coming up hey would
you be willing to try yes when could you
do that today
like that's how coaching works is that
like makes you be your own Savior
basically that I think a lot that's okay
and dang it they weren't wrong so I'm
always seeking calm but my whole like
atmosphere is always calm and quiet
because that's how I was raised be quiet
go to your room
and so that's what I try to recreate and
when I started to like let the music
take me and you as a DJ can appreciate
this I'm sure let the beat take you away
tears will just roll down my face and
like I get this huge release like what
the hell I need to incorporate more fun
and more play into my life because and
that's something to pay attention to is
if you're seeking constant like
meditation or the opposite where you're
seeking constant like go to the bar play
play play play play swap it try it do
something different for a one week and
see if you
anything that improves in your life yeah
I'm super into dislike trying things I
love that like if you just have like a
just give it a try seven days five days
two days even like one day one time
whatever just just give it a try what
are you so when you dance have you heard
of like ecstatic dancing I have and I
have this resistance towards it at the
retreat I just got back from they had
that one night and I went like no nope
and then I keeps popping up there's a up
north just a little bit I think it's
either in total and it's it's a newer
thing that I'm aware of I can camp
running wind or something like that they
do they host it they hosted all the time
there's the drum circles the meditation
things the I'll go with you
Oh seriously I'll do it okay oh maybe I
come too I'm a I've gotten better at
dancing by myself of this mic I'll put
up my mornings where I just I'll make
sure nobody's gonna walk through that
door you know I feel comfortable it just
feel beautiful and dance around you know
just whenever I got a feel that sounds
awesome though so so what do you think
like what do you think that is like
dancing right like it just does it move
our analytical mind out of the way you
think it breaks everything up a little
bit it breaks up like that static yeah
that's running three all the time
actually so crazy what you could see
that like the reason you're not doing it
is cuz of resistance but that's what you
know that you need to get through yeah
because I haven't so I'm what one thing
that I'm where I'm at now is allowing
myself to ask for help and for me that
means like a not doing everything by
myself so like my first yoga class was
like three weeks ago I've been doing
yoga by myself like every day for two
years my first yoga class ever was like
three weeks ago or a month ago or
something and it was it was because like
the other people like I was like I
really want to do it my way I don't like
to I'm like afraid of like what masks
and personas I turn on in front of other
people
well I imagine not I'm thinking about it
um that but I was crazy anxiety of that
particular night so I still any uh need
to like I'm gonna go again um but but
with with dancing I imagine that
rips down that like when you're dancing
around other people other people are not
that they look foolish but they're doing
the same movements as you we're all just
being a fool out there on the dance
floor is best doing the same matter yeah
and you're they're not even paying
attention to you yeah they're doing
their own thing so you pay attention to
yourself too and just like let go yeah
and so this whole process of like self
growth like as a coach I have to do the
work first and it's fast paced and it's
everyday and there's an assignment every
day it's kind of exhausting and
sometimes I just have to sit there in my
growth and acknowledge how far I've come
and then also I have to say like Who am
I sit here today I'm not gonna do
anything I'm not gonna do the work today
because I'm proud of how far I've come
yeah but then like with all the the the
forward momentum of it it feels good to
keep trying new things and there's many
laughable moments because listen up
calling myself out all day long and just
laughing at my rigidity or the
stubbornness or like how silly it might
have been for me to not try something
new like I was too far I was set in my
ways know my ways the best and if I just
let go of all of that and just try and
be more curious if you want playful like
have a more child's mind kind of even
though I'm an adult and I am a business
owner and all these things but no one to
let loose and it's such it's so amazing
in child mind I think I think we all
need to like not pretend we don't have
it like much like find it first where is
it yeah down under all that I think a
lot of you who like like when you see
cuz like I'm a DJ but like I had all
like social anxiety and depression and
all these things like when she and I
first got together like we would go out
to clubs and we would dance and like we
loved dancing and all these things but
then over the years I would start to get
like more and more self-conscious and
then it turned into like my stage
presence I'm like pretty much just like
wearing my hat as low as I can and
trying to like Bob my head forcibly you
know so far disconnected from what I
really started with which it was like
you know music and like just playing
music for other people is one of the
coolest things you could ever do right
and allowing your body to like be moved
by it like just to show ends how other
people are perceiving that moment like
you get to play the music and they get
to feel what you like I don't want them
to feel like the vibe and so I love and
respect what DJ's can do thank you
yeah I uh it's it's changed a lot over
the last of the last years for me but
it's something that I'll definitely hold
on to like it's something that like I
have some ideas and things that I've
been working on you know as far as like
a moment I really like the storytelling
like the I'm gonna I'm gonna take you
through this journey of like my inner
being through music but it's going to
point out things in your inner being you
know and I think that that like there's
so much power in that when it comes to
music like music because music is a very
like interesting thing like frequent
you